Contact

alex.oberhauser@networld.to

www.linkedin.com/in/ alexoberhauser (LinkedIn) www.alex-oberhauser.com (Portfolio) www.cambridge-blockchain.com (Other)

Top Skills

Blockchain Engineering Semantic Web Entrepreneurship

Languages

German (Native or Bilingual) English (Professional Working)

Publications

Recommendation of Mobile Services Employing Semantics and Community Generated Data

SESA: A Scalable Multi-Channel Communication and Booking Solution for e- Commerce in the Tourism Domain

Introduction of the Semantically Enabled Service Architecture to the Freight Domain

Patents

Systems and methods for secure custodial service

Systems and methods for managing relationships among digital identities

Systems and methods for managing digital identities

Alex Oberhauser &

Tech Entrepreneur, Innovator, C-Level Executive, Board Member Greater Boston Area

Summary

Started two companies in the blockchain space and has initiated a blockchain research project in the European Horizon 2020 FET-Open call. Worked on a bitcoin crowdfunding ecosystem, with related marketplace. Alex is holder of multiple US and international patents.

Alex Oberhauser is a passionate tech-entrepreneur and graduated computer scientist. He has co-founded the companies Sigimera Ltd. and Cambridge Blockchain Inc. Previously he started the incubator project Networld R&D. Currently he works on blockchain innovation, with a focus on practical real world applications, e.g. KYC/AML and Privacy compliance. Before focusing on blockchain, he has worked on crowd-funding and finance as a service. Additionally, he designed and build a production-ready Crises Information Service.

His work during the joint master degree of the University of Amsterdam and the VU Amsterdam has resulted in a new company and different research projects in the space. In the past Alex Oberhauser has worked for 4 years as researcher in the field of Semantic Web.

Specialties: Entrepreneurship, Blockchain, Scalable Web Applications, Semantic Web, Software Engineering, Computer Networks, Mobile Development

Experience

Cambridge Blockchain, Inc.
Founding Chief Technology Officer
August 2015 - Present (4 years 9 months)

Greater Boston Area

Alex is one of the co-founders and the original creator of the identity solution. As such he worked across different functional areas in the company, mainly as hands-on manager and as voting member of the board.

Cambridge Blockchain puts control of personal identity data back in the hands of the end user. Our platform allows financial institutions to meet the strictest new data privacy rules, eliminate redundant identity compliance checks and improve the customer experience.

Tags: Identity, Blockchain, Privacy, GDPR, KYC/AML Compliances

Networld R&D Founder & Project Lead 2006 - Present (14 years)

Networld R&D is the personal research and development meta-project of Alex Oberhauser. The main purpose of Networld is to advance innovations and provide the needed engineering tools to kickstart new projects. Currently the main focus is research and management for Blockchain related projects.

bitJob - Student Marketplace Advisor June 2017 - December 2017 (7 months) Tel Aviv Area, Israel

bitJob is a P2P MarketPlace for students, freelancers and employers, It's a social and ambitious Project, based on Blockchain technology, aimed at revolutionizing the way students make a living and gain occupational experience while still studying.

bitJob will offer the opportunity to receive immediate payment for students abilities and sharpen their skills while enriching their dynamic resume, anytime & anywhere!

bitJob is the professional version of Fiverr, same as LinkedIn is to Facebook.

Learn more at BitJob.io

Sigimera Ltd.
Founding Managing Director
2013 - 2016 (3 years)
London, United Kingdom

Alex Oberhauer is one of the Co-Founder of Sigimera Ltd. He has designed the architecture behind the Crises Information Platform and BTC-Funding.com, and implemented the backend logic.

Under his leadership multiple Horizon 2020 Future & Emerging Technology research proposals were submitted to the European Union Commission.

STI Innsbruck Junior Researcher May 2010 - April 2014 (4 years) Innsbruck, Austria

Implementing and analyzing Semantic Web Services. Integration of Semantic Technologies into Content Management Systems. Search Engine Optimization with the help of Semantic Technologies. Publication of Research Papers.

Education

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Master of Science (MSc), Computer Science · (2013 - 2015)

University of Amsterdam

Master of Science (MSc), Computer Science · (2013 - 2015)

Leopold-Franzens Universität Innsbruck
Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Science · (2013)

Commercial School A-Level, Economy